Matthew Thompson

mthompson.org m.r.thompson@bath.ac.uk Flat 5, Tanners Court Frenchay, Bristol, BS16 1RH +44(0)7450978201

Profile

I'm a graduate EngD student with the Centre for Digital Entertainment at the University of Bath, UK. Working together with Sysemia Ltd, my research focuses on using **semantic web** and **narratology** principles to **procedurally create non-linear, interactive narratives** for games, data visualisation and museum exhibits. There's a lot more to me than my interest in computers, though! I've volunteered and worked in many different countries around the world, interacting with many different people and cultures. My dream is to someday do something that combines these two passions.

Education

- University of Bath, UK
 - EngD doctorate in Digital Media, 2012 present (expected 2016 finish)
- University of York, UK
 - MSc degree in Natural Computation, 2012
- University of Exeter, UK
 - Upper Second Class (2:1) BSc degree in Computer Science, 2006

Publications & Research

- Effect of Touch-Screen Size on Game Immersion (Thompson, M. and Nordin, A.I. and Cairns, P.)
 - Presented at "HCI 2012 People and Computers XXVI" in Birmingham
- Research Internship, National Institute of Informatics (NII), Tokyo, Japan
 I spent the summer of 2013 at the NII in Tokyo, making ways of visualising and exploring their LODAC linked data ontology for Japanese museums.

Research Interests & Skills

- Procedural Interactive Narratives from Data
 - I am working together with Sysemia Ltd to use AI technologies to design interactive experiences such as games and museum exhibits.
- Procedural Generation

My MSc project was to procedurally generate 3D bridge designs by evolving and 'growing' them. Designs were then evaluated using the Bullet Physics Engine.

Mobile Application Development

I have had over a year of experience with developing applications for iOS (iPhone) and Android platforms.

Languages

C, C++, Objective C, Java Python, Ruby, Javascript, Coffeescript, Haskell, Clojure English (Native) Japanese (Advanced)

Work Experience

• Sysemia Ltd, Bristol, UK: 2013 - Present

Research Engineer

I do narratology, semantic web and visualisation research with Sysemia as part of my EngD doctorate with the University of Bath.

The Too Hard Basket, Australia: 2010 - 2011

iOS developer

I worked for this technology company in Australia, programming iOS and Android apps.

JET programme: Sano Board of Education, Sano, Japan: 2006 - 2010 Assistant Language Teacher

I was a teacher in four elementary schools, one junior high school and two senior high schools in Sano, Japan. Responsibilities included making lesson plans and occasionally presenting to an audience at teaching conferences.

References

• Dr Steve Battle, Sysemia Ltd

steve.battle@sysemia.co.uk +44 (0) 7823 695 290

• Dr Julian Padget, University of Bath

jap@cs.bath.ac.uk +44 (0) 1225 386 971